A Revelation in Entertainment!
Vogues of 1938 is a comedy, romance, music film directed by Irving Cummings.
An early Technicolor musical that concentrates on the fashions of the late 1930s,
this film was reissued under the title All This and Glamour Too.
The top models of the era, including several who are
advertising household products, are in the cast.
The plot centers around a chic boutique, whose owner, George Curson (Warner Baxter), tries
hard to please his customers while keeping peace with his unhappy wife.
A wealthy young woman, Wendy Van Klettering (Joan Bennett), decides to take a job as a model at the fashion house, just to amuse herself, but her
presence annoys Curson, who must put together the best possible show to compete with rival fashion houses at the Seven Arts Ball.
The film includes several hit songs, including the Oscar-nominated
"That Old Feeling" by Sammy Fain and Lew Brown.
George Curson, played by Warner Baxter.
Wendy Van Klettering, played by Joan Bennett.
Mary Curson, played by Helen Vinson.
Prince Muratov, played by Mischa Auer.
Henry Morgan, played by Alan Mowbray.
W. Brockton, played by Jerome Cowan.
Walter Wanger's Vogues of 1938 (also known by its shortened form, Vogues of 1938) is a 1937
musical comedy film produced by Walter Wanger and distributed by United Artists.
It was directed by Irving Cummings, written by Bella and Sam
Spewack, and starred Warner Baxter and Joan Bennett.
It was filmed in New York City in Technicolor.
It was nominated for two Academy Awards for Best Art Direction (Alexander Toluboff), and Best Original Song
(Sammy Fain (music) and Lew Brown (lyrics)) for the song That Old Feeling sung by Virginia Verrill.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.